Rory Malone

63 Garden Road. Richmond. TW9 4NR

rory-malone.com github.com/rnmalone rory.malone@hotmail.com mob: +44 7450889988

University of East London

PROFILE

An accomplished full stack developer with attention to detail and a perfectionist when building modern web applications. I have built a successful career using the latest technologies and have proven management skills leading a product download hub. Facing challenge using myriad experience and critical thinking I am always keen to lead and assist colleagues in the industry.

EDUCATION

Computer Science BSc

First class honors

September 2014 - 2017

ENTERPRISE TECHNOLOGIES Typescript, Node, Microsoft Azure, React, Redux, HTML5, Sass, Webpack, GraphQL, Express, SQL, REST, OAuth 2.0, Concourse

OTHER SKILLS

Web development, UX, SDL, DevOps, GIT workflow, Unix, threat modelling

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Developer

Sky

June 2021 - Present

London, UK

London, UK

As a senior member of the broadband team, my position has been in renovating an outdated stack to use bleeding edge technology to deliver a robust and maintainable product, generating a large portion of revenue for the business unit. My role has been overseeing the removal of 6 year old technology and practices and upgrading the stack with the latest version of React and it's best practices, replacing the antiquated functional and integration Ruby tests with Cypress, and delivering the application through continuous delivery Concourse pipelines. It has been my responsibility to highlight and prioritise weak points in the current stack and work to modernise them as soon as possible to ensure any production errors can be resolved as quickly as possible, as they contribute directly to negative image of the business.

Senior Full Stack Developer

August 2019 - June 2021

ARM holdings ltd. Cambridge, UK

Leading the development of a responsive web-app for high profile customers to download CPU intellectual property for one of the worlds best known semiconductor companies.

My responsibilities included:

- · Provide technical leadership for an agile team of developers and ensure the quality of the product is delivered with concise, well structured code.
- Translate complex business requirements from the product owner into arcane technical specifications and delegate to team members.
- Pioneering and rapid prototyping of high performance full stack solutions to phase out older technologies and practices.

- Responsible for deploying entire software stacks globally, configuring continuous zero-downtime delivery pipelines and alerting in Azure.
- Using the power of events and metrics to track user stories and model flows across our micro-services architecture to address latency and failures.
- Aggregate user events into metrics to drive the conception of new features.
- Presenting the above to upper business management and developers to prove the effectiveness of solutions.
- Key member of hiring team responsible for screening and interviewing new developers.
- Provide technical assistance for fellow developers of all abilities.

Full Stack Developer

British Telecom PLC Ipswich, UK

September 2017 - August 2019

- In a focused team at the heart of the company I have enjoyed developing software that links the cores business units together
- Building highly deployable, lightweight applications in the form of micro-services.
- Pioneering a new client server architecture to improve the process of authentication and authorization of our web applications.
- Front end strategy team player. I was responsible for pitching powerful presentations
 to illustrate ambitions for modernizing the team methodology and practices for the
 development and delivery of our products.

Key projects and deliverables:

- 999 Management Portal: A web interface for managing emergency service numbers, agents and various other facets, I was the front end developer responsible for delivering this important service for the upcoming upgrade of the 999 infrastructure.
- Service Gateway: Building scalable REST API that all of our products go through, I was a key developer in maintaining and implementing features for our API layer, a Node.js application that requires constant updates and testing to remain a reliable and secure server that all of our products rely on.
- Cisco services portal: Leading a team, I was managing the modernization of a service for BT customers to manage their business devices and features. Meeting the latest technology standards to deliver a versatile product to appeal to a wider international customer base.